<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<METS_Profile xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:METS="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profile_docs/mets.profile.v1-2.xsd
    http://www.loc.gov/METS/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd
    http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd
    info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2 http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/draft-schemas-2-0/premis-v2-0.xsd
    http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.loc.gov/standards/xlink/xlink.xsd">
    <URI LOCTYPE="URL">http://cdla.unc.edu/profiles/profile001.xml</URI>
    <title>Submission Profile for CDLA Simple Content Model</title>
    <abstract>This profile specifies how METS documents representing institutional repository
        submissions prepared by the Digital Production Center in the Carolina Digital Library and
        Archives should be encoded. This profile applies to simple file submissions not
        multi-part items, such as paged items.  See the wiki page (https://intranet.lib.unc.edu/trac/cdl/wiki/SimpleContentModel)
    	for more information about the Simple Content Model.</abstract>
    <date>2008-06-12T15:00:00</date>
    <contact>
        <name>Gregory Jansen</name>
        <institution>Carolina Digital Library and Archives, University of North Carolina at Chapel
            Hill</institution>
        <address>Wilson Library, UNC Campus, Chapel Hill, NC 27599</address>
        <email>count0@email.unc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <related_profile>There are no related profiles.</related_profile>
    <extension_schema>
        <name>PREMIS v2.0</name>
        <URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/draft-schemas-2-0/premis-v2-0.xsd</URI>
        <context>This schema is used for the contents of the &lt;digiProvMD&gt; and
            &lt;techMD&gt; elements within the &lt;amdSec&gt; elements.</context>
        <note>PREMIS elements will be used to record administrative metadata. Minimal PREMIS will
            include rights statements as well as digital provenance.  At a later date PREMIS may also be used in conjunction with
            other technical metadata to record physical characteristics of datastreams. However,
            this will not necessarily be required for the submission METS profile in the future as
            such data may be generated.</note>
    </extension_schema>
    <extension_schema>
        <name>MODS v3.3</name>
        <URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd</URI>
        <note>MODS elements will be used to record descriptive metadata for each object.</note>
    </extension_schema>
    <description_rules>
        <head>Collection and Container TYPEs</head>
        <p>These &lt;div&gt; TYPEs can only include files that are marked for use as SURROGATEs.</p>
        <head>Simple TYPE</head>
        <p>These &lt;div&gt; TYPEs can have files that are marked for any use in the controlled vocabulary, but they can only have one file marked as a MASTER and one file marked as INDEX_TEXT.</p>
    </description_rules>
    <controlled_vocabularies>
        <vocabulary>
            <name>CDLA Content Models</name>
            <maintenance_agency>Carolina Digital Library and Archives</maintenance_agency>
            <values>
                <value>Collection</value>
                <value>Container</value>
                <value>Simple</value>
            </values>
            <context>
                <p>This is the vocabulary for the TYPE attribute on each &lt;div&gt;.</p>
            </context>
            <description>
                <p>supported content types in this content model</p>
            </description>
        </vocabulary>
        <vocabulary>
            <name>CDLA File USE Attributes</name>
            <maintenance_agency>Carolina Digital Library and Archives</maintenance_agency>
            <values>
                <value>MASTER</value>
                <value>SERVICE</value>
                <value>INDEX_TEXT</value>
                <value>SURROGATE</value>
            </values>
            <context>
                <p>This is the vocabulary for the USE attribute on each &lt;file&gt;.</p>
            </context>
            <description>
            	<p>supported file usage patterns in this content model</p>
            </description>
        </vocabulary>
    </controlled_vocabularies>
    <structural_requirements>
    	<metsRootElement>
    		<requirement><p>A conforming METS document MUST have a PROFILE attribute indicating the following url:</p>
    			<p>http://cdla.unc.edu/mets-profiles/simple_model.xml</p>
    		</requirement>
    	</metsRootElement>
    	<metsHdr>
    		<requirement><p>A conforming METS document MUST contain a &lt;metsHdr&gt; with at least one valid &lt;agent&gt; having the
    			ROLE of CREATOR.</p></requirement>
    	</metsHdr>
        <dmdSec>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST contain one and only one &lt;dmdSec&gt;
                    corresponding to each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Simple" in the structure map.</p>
            </requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST contain one and only one &lt;dmdSec&gt;
        			corresponding to each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Collection" in the structure map.</p>
        	</requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MAY contain a &lt;dmdSec&gt;
        			corresponding to ANY &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Container" in the structure map.</p>
        		<p>Any Container without a corresponding &lt;dmdSec&gt; MUST have a LABEL attribute.</p>
        		<p>Container are not considered separate intellectual entities by this profile.  Instead they
        		are the organizing partitions within a collection.</p>
        	</requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST use an &lt;xmlData&gt; with a
                    &lt;mdWrap&gt; in each &lt;dmdSec&gt;. The &lt;xmlData&gt; must
                    contain a MODS element that is valid according to the MODS extension schema.</p>
            </requirement>
        </dmdSec>
    	<amdSec>
    		<requirement RELATEDMAT="CollectionAMD">
    			<p>A conforming METS document MUST contain a separate &lt;amdSec&gt; with a
    				single &lt;digiprovMD&gt; subelement for each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Collection" in the
    				structure map.</p>
    		</requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST contain a separate &lt;amdSec&gt; with a
                    single &lt;digiprovMD&gt; subelement for each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Simple" in the
                    structure map.</p>
            </requirement>
    		<requirement>
    			<p>ALL &lt;digiprovMD&gt; MUST use an &lt;xmlData&gt; with a
    				&lt;mdWrap&gt;. The &lt;xmlData&gt; must contain a PREMIS
    				&lt;premis&gt; container that is valid according to the PREMIS extension
    				schema.</p>
    		</requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY contain a separate &lt;amdSec&gt; with a
                    single &lt;techMD&gt; for each &lt;file&gt; with a USE of "MASTER". 
                    Each &lt;file&gt; with a corresponding &lt;techMD&gt; must reference
                    it by means of an AMDID attribute which matches the ID of the amdSec.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>ALL &lt;techMD&gt; MUST use an &lt;xmlData&gt; with a
                    &lt;mdWrap&gt;. The &lt;xmlData&gt; must contain a PREMIS
                    &lt;object&gt; container that is valid according to the PREMIS extension
                schema.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain a &lt;rightsMD&gt; element or
                    a &lt;sourceMD&gt; element. (These types of administrative metadata are
                    recorded in the main &lt;premis&gt; container, which is placed within the
                &lt;digiprovMD&gt;.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <head>Repository Hierarchy Requirement</head>
                <p>The entire submission package (SIP) MAY fall within a larger Container or Collection that is already in the repository.  (From these parent objects the deposited objects will eventually inherit some administrative properties, especially access controls.)  If the top &lt;div&gt; in the &lt;structMap&gt; is of TYPE "Collection" then the submission package stands alone as an ingest or update to a whole collection.</p>
                <p>If the top &lt;div&gt; is anything but a "Collection" then it MUST have a corresponding &lt;digiprovMD&gt;, see &lt;amdSec&gt; requirements.  The &lt;premis&gt; must contain an &lt;object&gt; which contains a &lt;relationship&gt;.</p>
            	<p>The PREMIS &lt;relationship&gt; MUST specify a info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isPartOf relationship to a parent object in the repository.  The &lt;relationship&gt; MAY specify the correct sub-type relationships from the list below, but this is not required:</p>
                <p>isSubsetOf (Container -> Container), isMemberOf (Simple -> Container), isMemberOfCollection (Container or Simple -> Collection)</p>
            	<p>The &lt;relatedObjectIdentification&gt; may use a repository path.</p>
                <p>An example using a repository path:
                	<![CDATA[
                    <relationship>
						<relationshipType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isPartOf</relationshipType>
						<relationshipSubType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isMemberOfCollection</relationshipSubType>
						<relatedObjectIdentification>
							<relatedObjectIdentifierType>http://www.lib.unc.edu/ir/definitions/ir-relsext-ontology.rdfs#repositoryPath</relatedObjectIdentifierType>
							<relatedObjectIdentifierValue>candid/reconstruction/alumni</relatedObjectIdentifierValue>
						</relatedObjectIdentification>
					</relationship>]]>
                </p>
            	<!--<p>An example using a GUID:
            		<![CDATA[
                    <relationship>
						<relationshipType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isPartOf</relationshipType>
						<relationshipSubType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isMemberOfCollection</relationshipSubType>
						<relatedObjectIdentification>http://www.lib.unc.edu/ir/definitions/ir-relsext-ontology.rdfs#
							<relatedObjectIdentifierType>HANDLE</relatedObjectIdentifierType>
							<relatedObjectIdentifierValue>http://lkjaljksda.edu/90209818.0912089123</relatedObjectIdentifierValue>
						</relatedObjectIdentification>
					</relationship>]]>
            	</p>-->
            </requirement>
        </amdSec>
        <fileSec>
            <requirement>
                <head>File Groups (&lt;fileGrp&gt;)</head>
                <p>Files MAY be grouped together in a &lt;fileGrp&gt; so that they are sets
                    of files that serve the same purpose. Examples include object surrogates,
                    service files and master files.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST have either it's own USE attribute or be under a
                    &lt;fileGrp&gt; that has a USE attribute. In both cases the USE
                    attribute MUST match a value in the CDLA File USE vocabulary.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST contain a &lt;FLocat&gt; element with
                    LOCTYPE of "URL" and an xlink:href attribute that points to a file within the SIP.
                    Use the local "file:" protocol prefix. (For example, a file in the root
                    Container of the archive is referenced by a URL such as "file:///foo.txt".)</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST have a correct MIMETYPE attribute.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MAY have an MD5 checksum in the CHECKSUM attribute.  If a CHECKSUMTYPE attribute is given, then it MUST be "MD5".</p>
            </requirement>
        </fileSec>
        <structMap>
            <requirement>
                <head>&lt;div&gt; Elements</head>
                <p>The &lt;div&gt; elements in the METS structure map are used to record
                    digital objects and their placement within the repository.</p>
                <p>Note that at some point Collections and Containers will be used as the
                    administrative domains within which their contents will be managed.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST have a TYPE attribute on every
                    &lt;div&gt;.  The TYPE must be taken from the CDLA Content Models vocabulary.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have an ID attribute unique to the document on
                    every &lt;div&gt;.  If an ID attribute is included, then this will be used as the contextually
                    unique slug for the object, which is used to construct a repository path and stable URL.</p>
            	<p>Note that the repository path is used to uniquely identify objects inside the repository.  If 
            	the repository path implied by the structure map is not unique, then your submission will need to be processed as an
            	update, which is not yet implemented.  SIPs containing objects that would conflict with the repository paths of existing
            	objects are rejected in their entirety.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST have a LABEL attribute for each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Container".  This
                will become the label property in Fedora and is used for display purposes within the context of the parent object.
                Therefore LABEL attributes should only distinguish each Container from it's siblings and should assume the context of the parent Container.</p>
            </requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT have a LABEL attribute for ANY &lt;div&gt; of TYPE "Collection" or "Simple".
        		(display labels for these objects will be extracted from required MODS elements.)</p>
        	</requirement>     
        	<requirement>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT have an ORDER attribute for ANY &lt;div&gt;.</p>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT have an ORDERLABEL attribute for ANY &lt;div&gt;.</p>
        	</requirement>      	
        </structMap>
    	
        <structLink>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain a &lt;structLink&gt;
                element.</p>
            </requirement>
        </structLink>
        <behaviorSec>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain a &lt;behaviorSec&gt;
                    element.</p>
            </requirement>
        </behaviorSec>
    </structural_requirements>

    <technical_requirements>
        <content_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>All files marked as USE MASTER or in a fileGrp marked as USE MASTER
                    MUST comprise a single complete representation of the work.</p>
            </requirement>
            <!--<requirement>
                <p>All master images referenced by a conforming METS document must be in ?????
                    format with a bit-depth of ?? and employing the ????? colorspace. The images
                    must contain a header element containing a copyright statement? The master
                    images must not employ watermarking technology.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>All web viewable derivative images referenced by a conforming METS document must
                    be in the Portable Network Graphics version 1.2 format with a bit-depth of 16
                    and employing the sRGB color space. The graphic must contain a tEXt chunk
                    containing a copyright statement?</p>
            </requirement>-->
            <requirement>
                <p>All surrogate images (thumbnails) referenced by a conforming METS document MUST be in the
                    Portable Network Graphics version 1.2 format with a bit-depth between 8 and 16
                    and employing the sRGB color space and a maximum resolution of 150 pixels on
                    either the X or Y axis. The graphic MUST contain a tEXt chunk containing a
                    copyright statement. Thumbnails images that are not rectangular in shape MUST
                    have an alpha layer.  (example of an image physical requirement)</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>All files marked for USE as INDEX_TEXT MUST be encoded in UTF-8 text/plain format without
                    markup.</p>
            </requirement>
        </content_files>
        <behavior_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>There MUST not be any behaviors associated with a conforming document.</p>
            </requirement>
        </behavior_files>
        <metadata_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>Any MODS XML embedded within a &lt;dmdSec&gt; MUST validate against the MODS extension schema specified above.</p>
            </requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<head>Minimal Descriptive Metadata for Simple Content</head>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST have a &lt;mods&gt; corresponding to each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE Simple.  This &lt;mods&gt; MUST contain
        		the following valid elements:</p>
        		<p>
        			TBD?!
        		</p>
        	</requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<head>Minimal Descriptive Metadata for Collections</head>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST have a &lt;mods&gt; corresponding to each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE Collection.  This &lt;mods&gt; MUST contain
        			the following valid elements:</p>
        		<p>
        			TBD?!
        		</p>
        	</requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Any PREMIS XML embedded within an &lt;amdSec&gt; MUST validate against the PREMIS extension schema specified above.</p>
            </requirement>
        	<requirement>
        		<head>Minimal Administrative Metadata for Collections and Simple Content</head>
        		<p>A conforming METS document MUST have a &lt;premis&gt; corresponding to each &lt;div&gt; of TYPE Simple.  This &lt;premis&gt; MUST contain
        			the following valid elements:</p>
        		<p>rights..
        			TBD?!
        		</p>
        	</requirement>
        </metadata_files>
    </technical_requirements>
    <tool>
        <description>
            <p>There MUST NOT be any particular tools associated with a conforming document.</p>
        </description>
    </tool>
    <Appendix NUMBER="1" ID="ex1">
 <METS:mets xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="
 http://www.loc.gov/METS/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd
 http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd
 info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2 http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/draft-schemas-2-0/premis-v2-0.xsd
 http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.loc.gov/standards/xlink/xlink.xsd"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:METS="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
	xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
	PROFILE="http://cdla.unc.edu/mets-profiles/simple_model.xml">

 	<METS:metsHdr>
 		<METS:agent ROLE="CREATOR">
 			<METS:name>Greg Jansen</METS:name>
 		</METS:agent>
 	</METS:metsHdr>
 	
 	<METS:dmdSec ID="SlidesMODS">
 		<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="MODS">
 			<METS:xmlData>
 				<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
 					<titleInfo>
 						<title>Digital Curation and Digital Preservation: An Introduction
 							(Presentation Slides)</title>
 					</titleInfo>
 					<genre>presentation slides</genre>
 					<name type="personal">
 						<affiliation>School of Information and Library Science, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<namePart>Hank, Carolyn</namePart>
 						<role>
 							<roleTerm>creator</roleTerm>
 						</role>
 					</name>
 					<name type="personal">
 						<affiliation>School of Information and Library Science, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<namePart>Tibbo, Helen</namePart>
 						<role>
 							<roleTerm>creator</roleTerm>
 						</role>
 					</name>
 					<originInfo>
 						<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">20070619</dateIssued>
 						<dateCreated encoding="iso8601">20070510</dateCreated>
 						<place>
 							<placeTerm authority="marcgac" type="text">e-gr</placeTerm>
 						</place>
 					</originInfo>
 					<language>
 						<languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
 					</language>
 					<physicalDescription>
 						<digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
 						<internetMediaType>application/vnd.ms-powerpoint</internetMediaType>
 					</physicalDescription>
 					<abstract>Slides from a half-day tutorial on digital curation and digital
 						preservation given June 19, 2007 at the ACM IEEE Joint Conference on Digital
 						Libraries (JCDL), held June 18-23, 2007, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</abstract>
 					<subject ID="owofjwe">
 						<topic>Digital Curation</topic>
 					</subject>
 					<extension>
 						<rdf:RDF>
 							<rdf:Description rdf:about="#owofjwe">
 								<das:rank xmlns:das="foo">4</das:rank>
 							</rdf:Description>
 						</rdf:RDF>
 					</extension>
 					<subject>
 						<topic>Digital Preservation</topic>
 					</subject>
 					<!-- the following might be added during ingest
 						<identifier type="URI" displayLabel="Unique Identifier">f23jkkhj23q23h23u34</identifier>
 						<identifier type="URL" displayLabel="Persistent/Citation URL">http://ir.unc.edu/f23jkkhj23q23h23u34</identifier> -->
 				</mods>
 			</METS:xmlData>
 		</METS:mdWrap>
 	</METS:dmdSec>
 	
 	<METS:dmdSec ID="OverviewMODS">
 		<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="MODS">
 			<METS:xmlData>
 				<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
 					<titleInfo>
 						<title>Digital Curation and Digital Preservation: An Introduction (Overview
 							Document)</title>
 					</titleInfo>
 					<genre>overview document</genre>
 					<name type="personal">
 						<affiliation>School of Information and Library Science, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<namePart>Hank, Carolyn</namePart>
 						<role>
 							<roleTerm>creator</roleTerm>
 						</role>
 					</name>
 					<name type="personal">
 						<affiliation>School of Information and Library Science, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<namePart>Tibbo, Helen</namePart>
 						<role>
 							<roleTerm>creator</roleTerm>
 						</role>
 					</name>
 					<originInfo>
 						<dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">20070619</dateIssued>
 						<dateCreated encoding="iso8601">20070510</dateCreated>
 						<place>
 							<placeTerm authority="marcgac" type="text">e-gr</placeTerm>
 						</place>
 					</originInfo>
 					<language>
 						<languageTerm authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
 					</language>
 					<physicalDescription>
 						<digitalOrigin>born digital</digitalOrigin>
 						<internetMediaType>application/vnd.ms-word</internetMediaType>
 					</physicalDescription>
 					<abstract>An overview, including agenda, objectives, and bibliography, from a
 						half-day tutorial on digital curation and digital preservation given June
 						19, 2007 at the ACM IEEE Joint Conference on Digital Libraries (JCDL), held
 						June 18-23, 2007, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</abstract>
 					<subject>
 						<topic>Digital Curation</topic>
 					</subject>
 					<subject>
 						<topic>Digital Preservation</topic>
 					</subject>
 					<!-- the following might be added during ingest
 						<identifier type="URI" displayLabel="Unique Identifier">f23jkkhj23q23h23u34</identifier>
 						<identifier type="URL" displayLabel="Persistent/Citation URL">http://ir.unc.edu/f23jkkhj23q23h23u34</identifier> -->
 				</mods>
 			</METS:xmlData>
 		</METS:mdWrap>
 	</METS:dmdSec>
 	
 	<METS:dmdSec ID="CollectionMODS">
 		<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="MODS">
 			<METS:xmlData>
 				<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
 					<titleInfo>
 						<title>Works of Carolyn Hank</title>
 					</titleInfo>
 					<genre>scholar collection</genre>
 					<name type="personal">
 						<affiliation>School of Information and Library Science, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<affiliation>Carolina Digital Library and Archives, UNC Chapel Hill</affiliation>
 						<namePart>Hank, Carolyn</namePart>
 						<role>
 							<roleTerm>contributor</roleTerm>
 						</role>
 					</name>
 				</mods>
 			</METS:xmlData>
 		</METS:mdWrap>
 	</METS:dmdSec>
 	
 	<METS:amdSec ID="CollectionAMD">
 		<METS:digiprovMD ID="CollectionDPMD">
 			<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="PREMIS">
 				<METS:xmlData>
 					<premis xmlns="info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2" version="2.0">
 						<object xsi:type="representation">
 							<objectIdentifier>
 								<objectIdentifierType/>
 								<objectIdentifierValue/>
 							</objectIdentifier>
 							<!-- This relationship element will be used to nest SIPs within containers -->
 							<!-- Collections do not require nesting -->
 							<!--							<relationship>
 								<relationshipType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isPartOf</relationshipType>
 								<relationshipSubType>info:fedora/fedora-system:def/relations-external#isMemberOfCollection</relationshipSubType>
 								<relatedObjectIdentification>
 								<relatedObjectIdentifierType>HANDLE</relatedObjectIdentifierType>
 								<relatedObjectIdentifierValue>http://lkjaljksda.edu/90209818.0912089123</relatedObjectIdentifierValue>
 								</relatedObjectIdentification>
 								</relationship>-->
 							<!--<preservationLevel>
 								<preservationLevelValue></preservationLevelValue>
 								</preservationLevel>-->
 						</object>
 						<rights>
 							<rightsStatement>
 								<rightsStatementIdentifier>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierType/>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierValue/>
 								</rightsStatementIdentifier>
 								<rightsBasis/>
 							</rightsStatement>
 						</rights>
 						
 					</premis>
 				</METS:xmlData>
 			</METS:mdWrap>
 		</METS:digiprovMD>
 	</METS:amdSec>
 	
 	<METS:amdSec ID="SlidesAMD">
 		<METS:digiprovMD ID="SlidesDPMD">
 			<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="PREMIS">
 				<METS:xmlData>
 					<premis xmlns="info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2" version="2.0">
 						<object xsi:type="representation">
 							<objectIdentifier>
 								<objectIdentifierType/>
 								<objectIdentifierValue/>
 							</objectIdentifier>
 						</object>
 						<rights>
 							<rightsStatement>
 								<rightsStatementIdentifier>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierType/>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierValue/>
 								</rightsStatementIdentifier>
 								<rightsBasis/>
 							</rightsStatement>
 						</rights>
 					</premis>
 				</METS:xmlData>
 			</METS:mdWrap>
 		</METS:digiprovMD>
 	</METS:amdSec>
 	
 	<METS:amdSec ID="OverviewAMD">
 		<METS:digiprovMD ID="OverviewDPMD">
 			<METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="PREMIS">
 				<METS:xmlData>
 					<premis xmlns="info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2" version="2.0">
 						<object xsi:type="representation">
 							<objectIdentifier>
 								<objectIdentifierType/>
 								<objectIdentifierValue/>
 							</objectIdentifier>
 						</object>
 						<rights>
 							<rightsStatement>
 								<rightsStatementIdentifier>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierType/>
 									<rightsStatementIdentifierValue/>
 								</rightsStatementIdentifier>
 								<rightsBasis/>
 							</rightsStatement>
 						</rights>
 					</premis>
 				</METS:xmlData>
 			</METS:mdWrap>
 		</METS:digiprovMD>
 	</METS:amdSec>

 	<METS:fileSec>
 		<METS:fileGrp>
 			<METS:file USE="MASTER" ID="PPT" MIMETYPE="application/vnd.ms-powerpoint">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///slides_tutorial10_final.ppt"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="SERVICE">
 			<METS:file ID="PPTPDF" MIMETYPE="application/pdf">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///tutorial10_slides_19june2007.pdf"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="INDEX_TEXT">
 			<METS:file ID="PPTTXT" MIMETYPE="text/plain">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///slides.txt"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="MASTER">
 			<METS:file ID="DOC" MIMETYPE="application/vnd.ms-word">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///outline_june18_5pm_CH.doc"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="SERVICE">
 			<METS:file ID="DOCPDF" MIMETYPE="application/pdf">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///tutorial10_overview_19june2007.pdf"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="INDEX_TEXT">
 			<METS:file ID="DOCTXT" MIMETYPE="text/plain">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///overview.txt"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 		<METS:fileGrp USE="SURROGATE">
 			<METS:file ID="THUMB1" MIMETYPE="image/png">
 				<METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///hank_carolyn.png"/>
 			</METS:file>
 		</METS:fileGrp>
 	</METS:fileSec>

 	<METS:structMap>
 		<METS:div ID="carolyn" TYPE="Collection"
 			DMDID="CollectionMODS" ADMID="CollectionAMD">
 			<METS:fptr FILEID="THUMB1"/>
 			<METS:div ID="jcdl2007" LABEL="Digital Curation Tutorial (JCDL 2007)" TYPE="Container">
 				<METS:div ID="slides" TYPE="Simple"
 					DMDID="SlidesMODS" ADMID="SlidesAMD">
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="PPT"/>
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="PPTPDF"/>
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="PPTTXT"/>
 				</METS:div>
 				<METS:div ID="overview" TYPE="Simple"
 					DMDID="OverviewMODS" ADMID="OverviewAMD">
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="DOC"/>
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="DOCPDF"/>
 					<METS:fptr FILEID="DOCTXT"/>
 				</METS:div>
 			</METS:div>
 		</METS:div>
 	</METS:structMap>
 	
</METS:mets>
    </Appendix>
</METS_Profile>
