<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<METS_Profile xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:METS="http://www.loc.gov/METS/"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS_Profile/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/profile_docs/mets.profile.v1-2.xsd
    http://www.loc.gov/METS/ http://www.loc.gov/standards/mets/mets.xsd
    http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd
    info:lc/xmlns/premis-v2 http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis/draft-schemas-2-0/premis-v2-0.xsd
    http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink http://www.loc.gov/standards/xlink/xlink.xsd">
    <URI LOCTYPE="URL">http://cdr.unc.edu/METS/profiles/Simple</URI>
    <title>Submission Profile for Carolina Digital Repository</title>
    <abstract>This profile specifies how METS documents for submissions to the Carolina Digital
        Repository should be encoded. This profile alone can describe annotated file structures, but
        may be extended to include more complex objects, such as multi-file media objects or paged
        items.</abstract>
    <date>2009-06-07T15:00:00</date>
    <contact>
        <name>Gregory Jansen</name>
        <institution>University Libraries, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</institution>
        <address>Davis Library, UNC Campus, Chapel Hill, NC 27599</address>
        <email>count0@email.unc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <related_profile>There are no related profiles.</related_profile>
    <extension_schema>
        <name>MODS v3.3</name>
        <URI>http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-3.xsd</URI>
        <note>MODS elements will be used to record descriptive metadata for each object.</note>
    </extension_schema>
    <description_rules> </description_rules>
    <controlled_vocabularies>
        <vocabulary>
            <name>CDR &lt;structMap&gt; TYPE Attributes</name>
            <maintenance_agency>Carolina Digital Repository</maintenance_agency>
            <values>
                <value>Basic</value>
            </values>
            <context>
                <p>This is the vocabulary for the TYPE attribute on the &lt;structMap&gt;
                    element.</p>
            </context>
            <description>
                <p>If a &lt;structMap&gt; type is omitted then Basic is implied.  Basic
                    &lt;structMap&gt;s are the only TYPE supported so far in this profile.
                    They can be used to represent Disks, Folders and Files.</p>
            </description>
        </vocabulary>
        <vocabulary>
            <name>CDR &lt;div&gt; TYPE Attributes</name>
            <maintenance_agency>Carolina Digital Repository</maintenance_agency>
            <values>
                <value>Disk</value>
                <value>Folder</value>
                <value>File</value>
                <!-- <value>Image</value> -->
                <value>Reference</value>
            </values>
            <context>
                <p>This is the vocabulary for the TYPE attribute on the &lt;div&gt;
                element.</p>
            </context>
            <description>
                <p>If a &lt;div&gt; type is omitted from the &lt;structMap&gt; then
                    Folder or File may be inferred from the context. (If a &lt;div&gt;
                    without explicit TYPE contains other &lt;div&gt;s, then it is a Folder,
                    otherwise it is a File.)</p>
                <p>Disk is used to represent an archived Disk file system, with contents and
                    metadata.</p>
                <p>Folder is used to represent a Folder within a file system. Folders may be used to
                    represent the content of Disk objects or on their own.</p>
                <p>File is used to represent a single file within a file system. File objects
                    include the master file. However, they also may include additional metadata
                    describing the master file. A File div bundles the master file together with
                    related metadata. Files may be used on their own, within a Folder or within a
                    Disk.</p>
                <p>Reference is used to include a div from a separate structMap, with a potentially
                    different object model, within a Disk or Folder. The reference MUST make use of
                    a structLink to associate the Reference with the other div.</p>
            </description>
        </vocabulary>
        <vocabulary>
            <name>CDR &lt;file&gt; USE Attributes</name>
            <maintenance_agency>Carolina Digital Repository</maintenance_agency>
            <values>
                <value>Master</value>
                <value>DiskImage</value>
                <value>Thumbnail</value>
            </values>
            <context>
                <p>This is the vocabulary for the USE attribute on each &lt;file&gt;.</p>
            </context>
            <description>
                <p>These use values give files a specific role within an object.</p>
                <p>Master is used for all the data files within an object that together comprise the
                    complete data representation upon submission. If a use value is not specified a
                    file is assumed to be a master file. Generally a single master file is
                    associated with a File div.</p>
                <p>DiskImage is used for archival disk image files. A single DiskImage file may be
                    specified only within a Disk object. The file MUST be a complete archival image
                    of the file system on the original physical disk. ISO image formats are strongly
                    encouraged, including ISO 9660 and ISO UDF.</p>
                <p>Thumbnail is used to specify a thumbnail image which may be used as a surrogate
                    for the object.</p>
            </description>
        </vocabulary>
    </controlled_vocabularies>
    <structural_requirements>
        <metsRootElement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST have a PROFILE attribute indicating the following
                    url:</p>
                <p>http://cdr.unc.edu/METS/profiles/Simple</p>
            </requirement>
        </metsRootElement>
        <metsHdr>
            <requirement>
                <p>At least one valid &lt;agent&gt; element with a ROLE attribute of CREATOR
                    and a TYPE attribute of INDIVIDUAL.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>At least one valid &lt;agent&gt; element with a ROLE attribute of
                    CUSTODIAN and a TYPE attribute of ORGANIZATION is recommended.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A CREATEDATE attribute is required containing a valid ISO 8601 date string.</p>
            </requirement>
        </metsHdr>
        <dmdSec>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY contain a &lt;dmdSec&gt; corresponding to
                    any &lt;div&gt; in the structure map.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST use an &lt;xmlData&gt; with a
                    &lt;mdWrap&gt; in each &lt;dmdSec&gt;. The
                    &lt;xmlData&gt; must contain a MODS element that is valid according to
                    the MODS extension schema.</p>
                <!-- TODO allow MODS to be xlinked -->
            </requirement>
        </dmdSec>
        <amdSec>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain any &lt;amdSec&gt;
                elements.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain any &lt;techMD&gt;
                elements.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain a &lt;rightsMD&gt; element or
                    a &lt;sourceMD&gt; element.</p>
            </requirement>
        </amdSec>
        <fileSec>
            <requirement>
                <head>File Groups (&lt;fileGrp&gt;)</head>
                <p>Files MUST be grouped together in one or more &lt;fileGrp&gt; elements, 
                    but there is no particular reason to use more than one at this time.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST have an ID attribute that is referenced by a &lt;fptr&gt; element
                    in the &lt;structMap&gt;.</p>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MAY have a USE attribute from the CDR file USE
                    Attribute vocabulary.</p>
                <p>A &lt;file&gt; with a USE attribute will be consider as a USE of
                    'Master'.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST contain a &lt;FLocat&gt; element with
                    LOCTYPE of "URL" and an xlink:href attribute that points to a resolvable URL.</p>
                <p>Resolvable URLs include those using a "file://" prefix that point at a file
                    bundled in the METS package. In these URLs the base directory and the root
                    directory both resolve to the top folder of the METS package. For example, a
                    file at the root of the archive can be referenced by an absolute URL such as
                    "file:///foo.txt" or a relative URL, such as "file://foo.txt". For security
                    reasons the "file://" prefix cannot be used to resolve files outside of the METS
                    package. Something like this, "file://../../../../etc/shadow" will result in an
                    error.</p>
                <p>Resolvable URLs include HTTP and HTTPS links that do not require a password. The
                    response should be the data file without intermediate pages. (client-side
                    redirects are not guarranteed to work)</p>
                <p>TODO: Resolvable URLs also include iRODS-style URLs that refer to zones federated
                    with the CDR, such as university libraries staging space.</p>
                <p>Relative paths may be used only for files with a METS bundle, omitting the
                    "file:" prefix.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MUST have a correct IANA MIMETYPE attribute.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>Each &lt;file&gt; MAY have an MD5 checksum in the CHECKSUM attribute. If
                    a CHECKSUMTYPE attribute is given, then it MUST be "MD5".</p>
            </requirement>
        </fileSec>
        <structMap>
            <requirement>
                <head>&lt;div&gt; Elements</head>
                <p>The &lt;div&gt; elements in the METS structure map are used to record
                    digital objects and their placement within the submission.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have a TYPE attribute on &lt;structMap&gt;
                    elements. If there is a TYPE attribute then it must be taken from the CDR structMap
                    TYPE Attribute vocabulary.  If no TYPE is given, then the &lt;structMap&gt; is assumed to be
                    "Basic".</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have a TYPE attribute on &lt;div&gt;
                    elements. If there is a TYPE attribute then it must be taken from the CDR div
                    TYPE Attribute vocabulary.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have an ID attribute unique to the document on
                    every &lt;div&gt;. If an ID attribute is included, then this will be
                    used to make the slug for the object, which is unique within the parent object
                    and used to construct a repository path and stable URL.</p>
                <!-- Note: the ID attribute is overloaded by use as a slug and as a reference in smLink.  Eventually
                    this could be a problem! -Greg -->
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY either have a LABEL attribute or a corresponding
                    dmdSec containing a MODS title for each &lt;div&gt; or both. The string
                    provided in one of these two ways will be used to label the object within the
                    context of the parent object. Therefore the string should distinguish each
                    object from it's siblings and may also assume the context of the parent object.
                    If both a LABEL and a MODS title are supplied, then the LABEL will be used for
                    this purpose.</p>
                <p>If neither of the strings above are provided, then a label of the form "Untitled
                    File 47" will be created, based on the position of the div within its sibling
                    divs.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have an ORDER attribute for any
                    &lt;div&gt;. The specified numeric order will be used to sort the object
                    with respect to it's siblings within the parent object. If no order is
                    explicitly specified then the order of div elements will be used.</p>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have an ORDERLABEL attribute for ANY
                    &lt;div&gt;. If an ORDERLABEL is included, then it will be appended to
                    the LABEL attribute.</p>
            </requirement>
        </structMap>

        <structLink>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY contain a &lt;structLink&gt; element, but
                    this behavior is not yet implemented. For now they are ignored!</p>
            </requirement>
        </structLink>

        <behaviorSec>
            <requirement>
                <p>A conforming METS document MUST NOT contain a &lt;behaviorSec&gt;
                    element.</p>
            </requirement>
        </behaviorSec>
    </structural_requirements>

    <technical_requirements>
        <content_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>All the files marked as USE MASTER or without a USE attribute MUST taken together
                    comprise a complete representation of the work.</p>
            </requirement>
            <!--<requirement>
                <p>All master images referenced by a conforming METS document must be in ?????
                    format with a bit-depth of ?? and employing the ????? colorspace. The images
                    must contain a header element containing a copyright statement? The master
                    images must not employ watermarking technology.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <p>All web viewable derivative images referenced by a conforming METS document must
                    be in the Portable Network Graphics version 1.2 format with a bit-depth of 16
                    and employing the sRGB color space. The graphic must contain a tEXt chunk
                    containing a copyright statement?</p>
            </requirement>-->
        </content_files>
        <behavior_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>There MUST not be any behaviors associated with a conforming document.</p>
            </requirement>
        </behavior_files>
        <metadata_files>
            <requirement>
                <p>Any MODS XML embedded within a &lt;dmdSec&gt; MUST validate against the
                    MODS extension schema specified above.</p>
            </requirement>
            <requirement>
                <head>Vocabularies for Descriptive Metadata</head>
                <p>A conforming METS document MAY have a &lt;mods&gt; element corresponding
                    to each &lt;div&gt; element.</p>
            </requirement>
        </metadata_files>
    </technical_requirements>
    <tool>
        <description>
            <p>There MUST NOT be any particular tools associated with a conforming document.</p>
        </description>
    </tool>
    <Appendix NUMBER="1" ID="ex1">
        <METS:mets xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
            xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/METS/ ../schemas/mets.xsd"
            xmlns:METS="http://www.loc.gov/METS/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
            xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
            PROFILE="http://cdr.unc.edu/METS/profiles/Simple">

            <METS:metsHdr CREATEDATE="2009-03-02T13:56:21.297-05:00">
                <METS:agent ROLE="CREATOR" TYPE="INDIVIDUAL">
                    <METS:name>Margaret Dickson</METS:name>
                </METS:agent>
            </METS:metsHdr>

            <METS:dmdSec ID="d3e2-MODS">
                <METS:mdWrap MDTYPE="MODS">
                    <METS:xmlData>
                        <mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3">
                            <mods:titleInfo>
                                <mods:title>Esperanza e insatisfacción adolescente en la novela
                                    española de finales del siglo veinte: graffiteros, okupas y
                                    soñadores</mods:title>
                            </mods:titleInfo>
                            <mods:genre authority="local">http://purl.org/eprint/type/Thesis</mods:genre>
                            <mods:typeOfResource>text</mods:typeOfResource>
                            <mods:name type="personal">
                                <mods:affiliation>Romance Languages</mods:affiliation>
                                <mods:namePart>Muñoz-Hermoso, Abel.</mods:namePart>
                                <mods:role>
                                    <mods:roleTerm>creator</mods:roleTerm>
                                </mods:role>
                            </mods:name>
                            <mods:originInfo>
                                <mods:dateIssued keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601"
                                >200605</mods:dateIssued>
                            </mods:originInfo>
                            <mods:language>
                                <mods:languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b"
                                >spa</mods:languageTerm>
                            </mods:language>
                            <mods:abstract>According to literary critic Juan Antonio Masoliver
                                Ródenas, Spanish novels written at the end of the twentieth century
                                reflected Spanish society's dissatisfaction with its government and
                                general pessimism. The purpose of this dissertation is to study five
                                Spanish novels written at that time--Martín Casariego's El chico que
                                imitaba a Roberto Carlos (1996), Lorenzo Silva's Algún día, cuando
                                pueda llevarte a Varsovia (1997), Ray Loriga's Héroes (1993), José
                                Ángel Mañas' Mensaka (1995), and Care Santos' Okupada (1997)--to
                                show that while some authors indeed provided a dark and negative
                                vision of Spanish society, others gave the reader a more optimistic
                                and positive image of the nation and its future. The texts chosen
                                for this study all present the world from the perspective of Spanish
                                adolescents and focus on the many different issues they must
                                confront in an increasingly globalized society. In order to
                                understand the context from which these novels originated, they are
                                analyzed from an urban and cultural perspective. This approach also
                                helps to establish a parallel between a young person’s coming-of-age
                                and the social, political and cultural changes taking place in Spain
                                at the turn the twenty-first century. Given the importance of the
                                development of identity in these texts, the correlation between the
                                Spanish adolescent novel and the tradition of the Bildungsroman is
                                also explored. A key to the process of identity development is the
                                different mechanisms young people rely on to escape (albeit
                                temporarily) from their problems. Some of the alternatives available
                                to adolescents presented in the texts studied here are the use of
                                the imagination, the development of an ecological consciousness, and
                                participation in social youth movements, such as painting graffiti
                                and squatter movements. In the end, the choices made by Casariego,
                                Silva, Loriga, Mañas, and Santos’ protagonists reveal the essential
                                differences among the Spanish novels written in the 1990s. By
                                presenting the reader with an image of youth that is hedonistic and
                                materialistic, Héroes and Mensaka confirm the critics’ assertion
                                that the Spanish novel reflected the nation’s disenchantment and
                                pessimism. However, the level of social engagement that motivates
                                the actions of the protagonists of El chico , Algún día, and Okupada
                                suggests that not all Spanish novelists viewed their nation from the
                                same negative perspective. What is more, the optimistic futures
                                suggested in these three novels positively influence young Spanish
                                readers at a time in their lives when they are developing their own
                                identity as individuals and social beings. By presenting characters
                                that face their problems and explore the various options available
                                to them, these authors indirectly help their adolescent readers who
                                are themselves living similar situations and in the process of
                                becoming adults.</mods:abstract>
                            <mods:accessCondition type="use">The author has granted the University
                                of North Carolina at Chapel Hill a limited, non-exclusive right to
                                make this publication available to the public. The author retains
                                all other rights.</mods:accessCondition>
                            <mods:accessCondition type="access">Open access</mods:accessCondition>
                        </mods:mods>
                    </METS:xmlData>
                </METS:mdWrap>
            </METS:dmdSec>

            <METS:fileSec>
                <METS:fileGrp>
                    <METS:file ID="diskimage" MIMETYPE="archive/iso9660" USE="DiskImage">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
                            xlink:href="http://darkive.lib.unc.edu/98274924.iso"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="image1" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL"
                            xlink:href="http://darkive.lib.unc.edu/98274924.tiff"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="r5" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///my file.doc"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="r6" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///my file.doc"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="r7" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///my file.doc"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="r8" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///my file.doc"/>
                    </METS:file>

                    <METS:file ID="r9" MIMETYPE="text/xml">
                        <METS:FLocat LOCTYPE="URL" xlink:href="file:///my file.doc"/>
                    </METS:file>
                </METS:fileGrp>
            </METS:fileSec>

            <METS:structMap ID="top">
                <METS:div TYPE="Disk" LABEL="Thomas Watson Digital Collection" ORDER="5">
                    <METS:div TYPE="Folder" LABEL="Correspondence Series" DMDID="d3e2-MODS">
                        <METS:div ID="corr1" LABEL="1873" ORDER="1" ORDERLABEL="1a"> </METS:div>
                        <METS:div ID="corr2" LABEL="1874" ORDER="2" ORDERLABEL="1b">
                            <METS:div TYPE="File">
                                <METS:fptr FILEID="r5"/>
                            </METS:div>
                            <METS:div TYPE="File">
                                <METS:fptr FILEID="r6"/>
                            </METS:div>
                            <METS:div TYPE="File">
                                <METS:fptr FILEID="r7"/>
                            </METS:div>
                            <METS:div>
                                <METS:fptr FILEID="r8"/>
                            </METS:div>
                            <METS:div LABEL="File McFileson">
                                <METS:fptr FILEID="r9"/>
                            </METS:div>
                        </METS:div>
                    </METS:div>
                    <METS:div TYPE="Reference" ID="ead1"/>
                </METS:div>
            </METS:structMap>

            <METS:structMap TYPE="Basic">
                <METS:div ID="i1" TYPE="File">
                    <METS:fptr FILEID="image1"/>
                </METS:div>
            </METS:structMap>

            <METS:structLink>
                <METS:smLink xlink:from="ead1" xlink:to="i1" xlink:arcrole="refersTo"/>
            </METS:structLink>
        </METS:mets>

    </Appendix>
</METS_Profile>
