<div class="contentarea about_page">

	<h2 class="fontface">Carolina Digital Repository (CDR) Collection Development Statement</h2>

<h3>Purpose of CDR</h3>

<p>The Carolina Digital Repository (CDR) is the primary digital preservation environment for objects managed by the UNC at Chapel Hill libraries. In some cases content in the CDR repository can be made available for end-user discovery and access. Rights and other issues may determine what levels of access can be provided to the material within the repository. Space constraints and technical feasibility may also determine what the library can deposit into the CDR.</p>

<h3>Purpose of Collection Development Statement</h3>
<p>This statement describes what streams of content are appropriate for deposit into the CDR. This document does not cover content or subject relevance. Curatorial units within Wilson Special Collections Library and the collections staff in the other libraries across campus are responsible for determining what content is in scope for selecting and acquiring based on subject relevance and archival value. </p>

<h3>Scope of CDR Content</h3>
<p>The content that will be deposited into the CDR is organized into three collecting areas: </p>

<ul class="contentul">
<li>born-digital special collections acquisitions,</li>
<li>faculty research/scholarship/creative work, and </li>
<li>digitized UNC at Chapel Hill library collections. </li>
</ul>

<h3>Born-digital special collections acquisitions</h3>
<h4>Born-digital body of work</h4>
<p>Born-digital bodies of work or portions of digital personal archives are materials created by a person or group of people to document their activities, such as creative works, activities within a business or research conducted. Materials in this category are like other acquisitions made by various collections units at UNC at Chapel Hill, differing primarily in their digital rather than analog nature. Examples may include but are not limited to: email correspondence, digital literary manuscripts, and research data.</p>

<h4>Electronic administrative records</h4>
<p>Electronic administrative records are those records created in electronic format by university units to document the actions and decisions of the university. The records that would be accepted into the repository would be those deemed of permanent value by the appropriate UNC at Chapel Hill records retention schedule. For more information, see this FAQ, http://www.lib.unc.edu/mss/uars/permfaq.html.</p>

<h4>Student organization digital objects</h4>
<p>Student organization digital objects are materials created by student organizations at UNC at Chapel Hill that serve as evidence of the student experience on campus. Examples may include, but are not limited to, student organization rosters, minutes from meetings and publicity from special events.</p>

<h3>Faculty and student research/scholarship/creative work</h3>
<h4>Pre/post prints</h4>
<p>Pre and post-prints are forms of publications that are used in various disciplines to share work earlier in the publication timeline. The CDR acquires pre and post-prints for preservation and to promote open access, and to redistribute in an institutional repository those works for which the author has retained that specific right. Works by, or co-authored by, UNC at Chapel Hill-affiliated faculty, staff, and students are in scope for the CDR.</p>

<h4>Grey literature/posters</h4>
<p>Grey literature is material that is not formally published, yet represents significant scholarship or creative work. These are often unique materials of high research value that won't be preserved or made accessible in another way. Examples include, but are not limited to, technical reports, white papers, research posters, and symposia proceedings. These materials could be generated at the university or by affiliated units or persons.</p>

<h4>Datasets</h4>
<p>Datasets are raw or processed collections of data, usually presented in a structured form, that are the product of one phase of research, and form the basis for further work. Datasets are created by activities across the sciences, social sciences, arts, and humanities. The CDR collects primary datasets or secondary datasets with substantial value added from university researchers and affiliated research institutes.  </p>

<h4>Learning objects</h4>
<p>Learning objects are a grouping of content that are used to meet learning objectives. This category includes instructional materials as well as primary sources placed in context for the purposes of teaching. The CDR collects learning objects that were developed or used at UNC at Chapel Hill. </p>

<h4>Electronic Theses, Dissertations, and other capstone works</h4>
<p>Theses, dissertations, and other capstone works created by students at UNC at Chapel Hill in order to support their candidacy for a degree are now often created and submitted in digital form. These scholarly works form a collection of scholarly output by students at the university, and as such are within the CDR's collection scope.</p>

<h3>Digitized UNC at Chapel Hill libraries collections</h3>

<h4>Digitized library collections</h4>
<p>Digitization of analog library collections, including print monographs and serials, manuscripts, maps, photographs, audio/visual materials, and musical scores is a strategic priority for the UNC at Chapel Hill libraries. In many cases, the CDR provides the preservation environment for the high resolution master files generated from this process. </p>

<h3>Digital materials collected by the library that are not currently deposited into the CDR</h3>

<h4>Web harvesting</h4>
<p>Web harvesting can be done to preserve websites of enduring value over time. A web crawler like the Internet Archive's Archive-It service or the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service usually does harvesting. The UNC at Chapel Hill libraries will likely rely on external services such as these for preservation of the products of the web harvesting process.</p>

<h4>Scanned books</h4>
<p>Bound monographs and serials digitized through the Internet Archive Scribe workflow are digitally preserved through the Internet Archive and the TRLN's membership in the HathiTrust. At this time, the UNC at Chapel Hill libraries does not seek to also manage preservation copies of these digital files through the CDR.</p>

<h4>Licensed electronic resources</h4>
<p>We aren't depositing into the CDR. We are relying on other efforts to preserve these materials such as Hathi Trust.</p>

</div>