<div class="contentarea about_page">
	<h2 class="fontface">How to contribute material to the CDR</h2>

	<h3>Depositing materials</h3>

	<p>UNC offers deposit, preservation and access services for your scholarly content
		through the CDR. Currently, all deposits into the CDR are mediated. 
		CDR staff will work
		with you to successfully deposit your materials and associated
		descriptive information.</p>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>
			Faculty or student sends email to
			<a href="mailto:cdr@unc.edu">cdr@unc.edu</a>
			expressing interest in depositing materials into CDR
		</li>

		<li>In consultation with repository staff or subject librarian,
			faculty or
			student will fill out an Ingest Survey. The Ingest Survey is reviewed
			by repository staff.</li>
		<li>Once collection is deemed appropriate for deposit, faculty or
			student will
			sign the relevant deposit agreement.</li>
		<li>Repository staff will gain access to materials. If there are any
			questions,
			library staff will contact the depositor.</li>
		<li>Repository staff will notify depositor when materials are
			successfully uploaded
			into the CDR and will provide a URL to the material.</li>
	</ul>

	<h3>Rights</h3>

	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>When you deposit works into the CDR, you do not give up your
			copyright to the
			material. The University of North Carolina does not seek nor claim
			copyright on material deposited into the CDR. We do ask for a
			Non-Exclusive License in order to make the material available on the
			web.</li>
		<li>
			<a href="external?page=about.nonexclusiveDepositLicense">Non-Exclusive Deposit License</a>
		</li>
	</ul>

	<h3>Preservation</h3>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>The chief purpose of the CDR is to provide for the long-term
			preservation of
			materials created by members of the UNC-Chapel Hill community.</li>

		<li>
			<a href="external?page=about.preservationAndStewardship">Preservation and Stewardship Policy</a>
		</li>
	</ul>

	<h3>How to prepare a collection for deposit</h3>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>
			Organizing your files
			<ul class="contentul">
				<li>Implement a file-naming convention that is simple, easy to
					remember and use.
					Use consisting file naming throughout the project.</li>
			</ul>

		</li>
		<li>
			Metadata
			<ul class="contentul">
				<li>Metadata, or data about data, is essential for long-term access
					to and
					discovery of your material.</li>
				<li>Get in touch with your subject librarian or repository staff to
					find out how
					to ensure you are creating metadata that will ensure discovery of
					your research.</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
		<li>
			Identifying material with access restrictions
			<ul>

				<li>Some materials in collections may contain sensitive information.
					Depositors need to identify these files so repository staff can
					successfully provide access control.</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
	</ul>
</div>