<div class="contentarea about_page">
	<h2 class="fontface">Policies &amp; Guidelines</h2>
	<h3>Organization</h3>

	<p>The CDR is organized by departmental affiliations. Any university
		college, school, department, program or research center may make a
		request to create a presence on the CDR.  
        </p>
	<h3>Criteria for Inclusion</h3>
	
	<p><a href="external?page=about.collectionPolicy">Collection Development Policy</a></p>
	
	<p>Digital objects eligible for inclusion in the CDR include works of a
		scholarly or creative nature, as well as university records kept in
		accordance with the North Carolina Public Records Law that have a
		permanent retention. These object types may include, but are not
		limited to: 
        </p>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>Publications
          </li>
		<li>Unpublished Scholarly Works
          </li>
		<li>Datasets
          </li>
		<li>Research materials
          </li>
		<li>Learning Materials
          </li>
		<li>Institutional Records
          </li>
		<li>Electronic Theses and Dissertations
          </li>
		<li>Audio or Visual Files
          </li>

	</ul>
	<p>CDR submissions must be produced, submitted or collected by UNC-CH
		faculty, researchers, staff or students.   
        </p>
	<h3>Withdrawal from the CDR</h3>
	<p>For information about contacting the library about the removal of
		content from the CDR, please refer to the Take Down Policy.  
        </p>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>
			<a href="external?page=about.takeDownPolicy">Take Down Policy</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
	<h3>Rights</h3>

	<p>If the depositor holds the copyright, s/he retains copyright of
		materials deposited in the CDR. The CDR requires that the copyright
		holder allows the non-exclusive distribution and preservation of the
		work when depositing content. 
        </p>
	<p>For special circumstances, arrangements can be made to place a
		temporary embargo on distribution or to restrict access to a specific
		community. 
        </p>
	<p>For unpublished work, the author/creator usually can negotiate
		institutional repository permissions with the publisher prior to
		publication. Contact the library for assistance with modifying a
		publisher agreement or use the SPARC Author's Addendum. For an online
		version of this form or for more information about author rights,
		visit SPARC Author Rights. 
        </p>
	<p>
		Copyright holders may prefer to use the Creative Commons Licensing
		Model. This model is an alternative to conventional copyright in that
		it allows the creator to define the spectrum of possibilities between
		full copyright with all rights reserved and public domain where no
		rights are reserved. Full descriptions of the licensing options are
		available at
		<a href="http://creativecommons.org/about/licenses/">http://creativecommons.org/about/licenses/</a>
		.
	</p>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>

			<a href="external?page=about.nonexclusiveDepositLicense">Non-Exclusive Deposit License</a>

		</li>
	</ul>
	<h3>Preservation and Stewardship</h3>
	<p>For more information about the stewardship and long-term
		preservation of materials deposited into the CDR, please refer to the
		Preservation and Stewardship Policy.
        </p>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>
			<a href="external?page=about.preservationAndStewardship">Preservation and Stewardship Policy</a>

		</li>
	</ul>

	<p>
		For more information about formats, metadata and other technical
		questions, please
		<a href="external?page=contact">contact us</a>
		.
	</p>

</div>
