<div class="contentarea about_page">
	<h2 class="fontface">Preservation and Stewardship</h2>

	<p>The Carolina Digital Repository (CDR) manages the infrastructure and
		services necessary to provide sustainable access to digital objects.
	</p>
	<p>The CDR is designed and operated to ensure the integrity of digital
		files at a bitstream level (the way information is encoded).
		Characteristics that will affect preservation are recorded in metadata
		as part of the deposit process. The CDR regularly verifies the
		integrity of files, maintains a record of preservation-related
		actions,
		and employs best practices in the field for persistent storage,
		including back-up and recovery procedures.</p>
	<p>Repository staff consult with prospective depositors regarding the
		nature of their digital collections, foreseeable challenges for
		long-term access, and strategies for meeting their preservation goals.
	</p>

	<h3>Services Provided</h3>

	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>Consult with pilot collection contributors for preparation of
			submission of content into the CDR</li>
		<li>Capture descriptive information about digital objects</li>

		<li>
			Create and maintain service application, including:
			<ul class="contentul">
				<li>Search</li>
				<li>Display</li>
				<li>Export</li>
			</ul>
		</li>

		<li>Provide and manage sufficient storage for ingest and maintenance
			of
			content and associated metadata</li>
		<li>Provide and manage persistent storage, including appropriate
			back-up and recovery procedures</li>
		<li>Sustain bitstream-level preservation of digital objects</li>
		<li>Perform system monitoring, testing and debugging</li>
	</ul>

	<h3>Caveats</h3>
	<ul class="contentul">

		<li>Services provided by the CDR reflect the repository's stage of
			development and implementation of evolving standards and best
			practices in the field. As the repository grows and the technology
			matures, so will the CDR's capabilities for preservation and access.
		</li>
	</ul>
</div>