<div class="contentarea about_page">
	<h2 class="fontface">Repository FAQ</h2>
	<ul class="contentul">
		<li>

			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#why">Why should I deposit my material into the Carolina Digital
				Repository?</a>
		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#what">What happens to my material once I deposit into the CDR?
			</a>
		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#accept">Does the CDR accept only digital files?</a>
		</li>
		<li>

			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#better">Why is the CDR a better place for my work than my
				departmental web page?</a>
		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#type">What type of materials can I submit to the CDR?</a>
		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#access">How does access work?</a>

		</li>
		<li>
			<a href="/scontent/aboutPages/repoFAQ.xml#time">How long does the whole process take (from contacting CDR
				staff to having my materials accessible in the CDR)?</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
	<a id="why"></a>
	<h3>Why should I deposit my material into the Carolina Digital
		Repository?</h3>
	<p>The CDR provides a secure home for your research and scholarly work.
		The University and the Library are committed to providing long-term
		access to materials placed in the repository, and are vigilant about
		securing and backing up data.</p>

	<p>In addition, CDR employs standards that allow materials to be
		discovered and indexed by public search engines such as Google and
		Google Scholar, if you so choose. This makes your work accessible for
		your continued research and the work of others.</p>

	<a id="what"></a>
	<h3>What happens to my material once I deposit into the CDR?</h3>

	<p>
		Materials are accessible via the CDR website. Deposited materials will
		be keyword indexed and searchable. Copies of material can be returned
		to the depositor, if needed. We strive to permanently maintain
		materials in the repository, but if there is a need to remove
		material, please refer to our
		<a href="scontent/aboutPages/takeDownPolicy.xml">Take Down Policy</a>.
	</p>
	<a id="accept"></a>
	<h3>Does the CDR accept only digital files?</h3>
	<p>The CDR does not digitize materials as part of its current services.
		We currently only accept material in digital form. 
		Please contact the <a href="http://cdla.unc.edu/">Carolina Digital Library and Archives</a> to learn more
		about their digitization services. 
          </p>
	<a id="better"></a>
	<h3>Why is the CDR a better place for my work than my departmental web
		page?</h3>
	<p>Once submitted to CDR, your digital scholarship will be part of a
		systematic digital preservation program so that years from now, you
		and others can count on accessing and using your research. You submit
		the material and CDR takes care of the rest.  
          </p>
	<a id="type"></a>
	<h3>What type of materials can I submit to the CDR?</h3>

	<p>The CDR can accept most file formats, but CDR staff may want to
		consult with you before depositing materials in rare or obsolete file
		formats. The CDR makes audio and video files available for download,
		but does not provide streaming.
          </p>
	<a id="access"></a>
	<h3>How does access work?</h3>
	<p>The majority of material in the CDR is available to the public.
		Depositors can set the policies to restrict access to their materials.
		CDR will work with depositors to set up the necessary access control.
	</p>
	<a id="time"></a>
	<h3>How long does the whole process take (from contacting CDR staff to
		having my materials accessible in the CDR)?</h3>
	<p>The timeline depends on the size and complexity of the collection.
		CDR staff will first meet with you to fill out a survey about your
		collection and become more familiar with the materials. Once the
		survey is complete, CDR staff will coordinate preparation of technical
		data and transfer of the collection. 
          </p>

</div>
