<div class="contentarea about_page">
	<h2 class="fontface">Technology Overview</h2>

	<h3>Architecture Overview</h3>

	<p>The University Library, with the cooperation of the School of Information and Library 
	Science and the <a href="http://dice.unc.edu/">Data Intensive Cyberinfrastructure Environments 
	(DICE) Center</a>, is actively developing the repository. Following standards developed 
	in the reference model for an Open Archival Information Systems, the CDR employs 
	the <a href="http://fedora-commons.org/">Fedora Commons Repository</a> as an object, 
	model and services provider and <a href="https://www.irods.org/">iRODS</a> as a distributed
	storage and preservation system.</p>
	
	<p> The University Library is a partner in the Policy-Driven Repository Infrastructure project 
	funded by the Institute for Museum and Library Services (IMLS) to build on the initial 
	Fedora to iRODS connector and investigate interoperability issues in greater depth. UNC 
	Libraries efforts with respect to the CDR are based on connecting these two technologies.</p>

	<p>In partnership with the <a href="http://www.renci.org/">Renaissance Computing Institute 
	(RENCI)</a>, Duke University and North Carolina State University, the University 
	Library and UNC Information Technology Services are participating in a project funded 
	by the <a href="http://www.rtp.org/main/index.php?pid=53&amp;sec=1">Triangle University Center 
	for Advanced Studies, Inc. (TUCASI)</a> to develop policies and infrastructures that will
	support the federation of independent repositories built on diverse hardware and software 
	platforms. The CDR will form one of UNC's core technologies for this project.</p>
	<br/>
	<h3>Technology overview</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>Solr</li>
		<li>Spring framework</li>
		<li>Fedora</li>
		<li>iRods</li>
		<li>FITS</li>
		<li>imagemagick</li>
		<li>Eclipse Modeling Framework</li>
		<li>Shibboleth</li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	<img src="/static/aboutPages/CDRSystemOverview.png" class="diagram"/>
	<br/>
	<br/>
	<h3>Standards and Protocols Used</h3>
	<ul>
		<li>METS (for SIP transmission)</li>
		<li>MODS (used for descriptive schema within CDR)</li>
		<li>PREMIS (used to document preservation events)</li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	<br/>
	<h3>Ingest Workflow</h3>
	
	<img src="/static/aboutPages/workbenchworkflow.png" class="diagram" style="width: 800px; height: 306px;"/> 
</div>